{
    "id": "6907574bbeb24d128e36a8e83fb573e2",
    "title": "Parts Of Speech Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "New brooms sweep clean. Here clean is an ………………….",
            "description": "Here clean modifies the verb sweep and hence it is an adverb.",
            "answers": [
                "adjective",
                "adverb",
                "verb"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "A burnt child dreads fire. Here burnt is an …………………….",
            "description": "Burnt is used as an adjective because it modifies the noun child.",
            "answers": [
                "adjective",
                "adverb",
                "verb"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The streets of some of our cities are noted for their crookedness. Here crookedness is a/an ………………………..",
            "description": "Crookedness is an abstract noun.",
            "answers": [
                "adjective",
                "noun",
                "verb"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Talking too much is a sign of vanity. Here sign is a/an …………………………",
            "description": "Sign is a noun. Only nouns can be used with articles.",
            "answers": [
                "pronoun",
                "noun",
                "adjective"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "My views on this are quite different. Here quite is a/an ………………………….",
            "description": "Here quite is an adverb because it modifies the adjective different.",
            "answers": [
                "preposition",
                "adjective",
                "adverb"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "No man can serve two masters. Here serve is a/an ……………………",
            "description": "Serve is a verb. Verbs are action words.",
            "answers": [
                "conjunction",
                "adverb",
                "verb"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Sam plays football very well. Here well is a/an …………………",
            "description": "Here the word well modifies the verb plays. Adverbs are words used to modify verbs.",
            "answers": [
                "verb",
                "adverb",
                "adjective"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The boy ran across the road. Here across is a ……………………..",
            "description": "A preposition is a word that shows how the noun that follows it is connected to another word in the sentence. ",
            "answers": [
                "noun",
                "conjunction",
                "preposition"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The cat was hiding behind the curtain. Here behind is a ………………………..",
            "description": "A preposition is a word that shows how the noun that follows it is connected to another word in the sentence. ",
            "answers": [
                "preposition",
                "conjunction",
                "verb"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I waited for him until he came. Here until is a …………………….",
            "description": "A conjunction is a word used to connect two clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "preposition",
                "conjunction",
                "interjection"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Rahim put the books on the table. Here put is a/an ……………………..",
            "description": "Verbs are action words.",
            "answers": [
                "verb",
                "noun",
                "pronoun"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She can speak English fluently. Here fluently is a/an ………………………",
            "description": "Here the word fluently modifies the verb speaks. Adverbs are words used to modify verbs. ",
            "answers": [
                "adjective",
                "adverb",
                "conjunction"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}